Finding Aid for the Ruth Bernstein Papers, 1945 - 1949 CA.MS.00358
Smith College Archives
Ruth Bernstein papers
1945-1949
Smith College Archives
Bernstein, Ruth (Class of 1949)
CA.MS.00358
0.417 linear feet (1 container)
Alumna, Class of 1949. Contains correspondence, class notes and pamphlets.
Biographical / Historical
Please contact the College Archives for Ruth Bernstein's biographical information.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains correspondence written by Ruth "Babs" Bernstein to her parents and sister "Mar". A dedicated correspondent, the collection contains daily and weekly letters from the entirety of her first year through her junior year at Smith College. The collection also contains a few letters received during her time at Smith College as well as a number of pamphlets, flyers, and class notes from 1945 - 1949.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series:
Correspondence Sent
Correspondence Received
APPENDIX: subject index
This guide to topics found within this collection was prepared by Hilary Buxton.
Amherst College 10/17/1945
10/29/1945
11/11/1945
4/21/1946
3/15/1948
Social Life 11/7/1945
11/24/1945
3/18/1946
4/28/1946
5/6/1946
5/16/1946
College Curriculum 5/16/1946
4/17/1947
4/21/1947
Arts, Drama, and Music 10/25/1945
12/6/1945
12/17/1945
11/12/1946
1/21/1946
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Ruth Bernstein Papers, 1945 - 1949 were created by Ruth Bernstein and donated to the College Archives at the Class of 1949's 50th reunion in May, 2009.
correspondence; Smith College -- Students; Smith College -- Social life and customs -- Sources; Smith College -- Alumni and alumnae -- History -- Sources
- Series I: Correspondence Sent, 1945-1949
  - September - October, 1945 (Box 2170.2, Folder 1)
  - November - December, 1945 (Box 2170.2, Folder 2)
  - January - February, 1946 (Box 2170.2, Folder 3)
  - March - April, 1946 (Box 2170.2, Folder 4)
  - May - June, 1946 (Box 2170.2, Folder 5)
  - December, 1946 - April, 1947, 1946-1947 (Box 2170.2, Folder 6)
  - May - June, 1947 (Box 2170.2, Folder 7)
  - September - October, 1947 (Box 2170.2, Folder 8)
  - November - December, 1947 (Box 2170.2, Folder 9)
  - January - February, 1948 (Box 2170.2, Folder 10)
  - March - April, 1948 (Box 2170.2, Folder 11)
- Series II: Correspondence Received, 1945-1949
  - December, 1945 - February, 1946, 1945-1946 (Box 2170.2, Folder 12)
  - miscellaneous, 1945-1948 (Box 2170.2, Folder 13)
  - class notes, 1945-1948 (Box 2170.2, Folder 14)